<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Academic</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the demand driven system on earnings.</title>
      <link>/project/higher_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/higher_education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The human capital literature has often taken as sacrosanct that an increase in the number of years of schooling leads to an increase in the wage premium. However a less well-understood element of the research is whether a large increase in the supply of graduates will, over time, reduce the wage premium of a university degree. In this paper, we use a sudden policy decision by Australia&amp;rsquo;s Federal Government in 2010, to expand the number of university places, to test the impact of an increase in the number of graduates on the wage premium of certain occupations. We analyse a longitudinal dataset of Australian taxpayers produced by the Australian Tax Office and find that completing a degree after the policy was introduced is associated with a log wage reduction of 8 percent. By occupations, we find that the negative effects persisted for engineering and accounting in all specifications of the model. Nursing and teaching were negative in most specifications of our model but were not robust to the inclusion of gender-cohort interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skill mismatch and migrants</title>
      <link>/project/skilled_permanent_migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/skilled_permanent_migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020, CEDA will release a report that will focus on Australia&amp;rsquo;s permanent skilled migration program.
In CEDA’s 2019 report, the Effects of Temporary Migration, we looked at Australia’s temporary skilled migration system and the effects of recent migrants on local workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEDA’s second report on immigration takes a different angle – does our permanent migration system effectively utilise the skills of migrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report will look at the extent of skill mismatch in the permanent migrant labour market, particularly among permanent skilled migrants and will identify policies that would help alleviate this issue. It will also make recommendations on how to improve the process through which skills shortages are identified and communicated to prospective migrants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking data in the public interest</title>
      <link>/project/unlocking_data_public_interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/unlocking_data_public_interest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
